<root>
    <title>Alexander Hamilton</title>

    <stageDirection>Lights up on Aaron Burr &amp; the company.</stageDirection>

    <sp>
        <speaker who="burr">AARON BURR</speaker> How does a bastard, orphan, son of a whore and a<lb/>
        Scotsman, dropped in the middle of a forgotten<lb/> Spot in the Caribbean by providence,
        impoverished, in squalor<lb/> Grow up to be a hero and a scholar?<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="laurens">JOHN LAURENS</speaker> The ten-dollar Founding Father without a father<lb/> Got a
        lot farther by working a lot harder<lb/> By being a lot smarter<lb/> By being a
        self-starter<lb/> By fourteen, they placed him in charge of a trading charter<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="jefferson">THOMAS JEFFERSON</speaker> And every day while slaves were being slaughtered and
        carted<lb/> Away across the waves, he struggled and kept his guard up<lb/> Inside, he was
        longing for something to be a part of<lb/> The brother was ready to beg, steal, borrow, or
        barter<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="madison">JAMES MADISON</speaker> Then a hurricane came, and devastation reigned<lb/> Our man
        saw his future drip, dripping down the drain<lb/> Put a pencil to his temple, connected it
        to his brain<lb/> And he wrote his first refrain, a testament to his pain<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="burr">BURR</speaker> Well, the word got around, they said, “This kid is insane, man”<lb/>
        Took up a collection just to send him to the mainland<lb/> “Get your education, don’t forget
        from whence you came, and<lb/> The world's gonna know your name. What’s your name,
        man?”<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="hamilton">ALEXANDER HAMILTON</speaker> Alexander Hamilton<lb/> My name is Alexander
        Hamilton<lb/> And there’s a million things I haven’t done<lb/> But just you wait, just you
        wait...<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="eliza">ELIZA HAMILTON</speaker> When he was ten his father split, full of it,
        debt-ridden<lb/> Two years later, see Alex and his mother bed-ridden<lb/> Half-dead sittin'
        in their own sick, the scent thick<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="company">FULL COMPANY EXCEPT HAMILTON <stageDirection>whispering</stageDirection></speaker>
        And Alex got better but his mother went quick<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker who="washington">GEORGE WASHINGTON</speaker> Moved in with a cousin, the cousin committed
        suicide<lb/> Left him with nothin’ but ruined pride, something new inside<lb/> A voice
        saying<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker> “You gotta fend for yourself.”<lb/>
    </sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> “Alex, you gotta fend for yourself.”<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker> He started retreatin’ and readin’ every treatise on the
        shelf<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>BURR</speaker> There would have been nothin’ left to do<lb/> For someone less
        astute<lb/> He woulda been dead or destitute<lb/> Without a cent of restitution<lb/> Started
        workin’, clerkin’ for his late mother’s landlord<lb/> Tradin’ sugar cane and rum and all the
        things he can’t afford<lb/> Scammin’ for every book he can get his hands on<lb/> Plannin’
        for the future see him now as he stands on<lb/> The bow of a ship headed for a new land<lb/>
        In New York you can be a new man <lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> Scammin’<lb/> Plannin’<lb/> Oooh...<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> In New York you can<lb/> Be a new man—<lb/> In New York you
        can<lb/> Be a new man—<lb/>
    </sp>

    <sp><speaker>HAMILTON</speaker> Just you wait!<lb/> Just you wait!<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> In New York you can be a new man—<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>WOMEN</speaker> In New York— <lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>MEN</speaker> New York—<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>HAMILTON</speaker> Just you wait!<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> Alexander Hamilton<lb/> We are waiting in the wings for you<lb/>
        You could never back down<lb/> You never learned to take your time!<lb/> Oh, Alexander
        Hamilton<lb/> When America sings for you<lb/> Will they know what you overcame?<lb/> Will
        they know you rewrote the game?<lb/> The world will never be the same, oh<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>BURR</speaker> The ship is in the harbor now<lb/> See if you can spot him<lb/>
        Another immigrant<lb/> Comin’ up from the bottom<lb/> His enemies destroyed his rep<lb/>
        America forgot him <lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> Alexander Hamilton<lb/> Waiting in the wings for you<lb/> You
        never learned to take your time!<lb/> Oh, Alexander Hamilton<lb/> Alexander Hamilton…<lb/>
        America sings for you<lb/> Will they know what you overcame?<lb/> Will they know you rewrote
        the game?<lb/> The world will never be the same, oh<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>MEN</speaker> Just you wait<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> Just you wait<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>MULLIGAN/MADISON &amp; LAFAYETTE/JEFFERSON</speaker> We fought with him<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>LAURENS/PHILIP</speaker> Me? I died for him<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>WASHINGTON</speaker> Me? I trusted him<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>ELIZA &amp; ANGELICA &amp; PEGGY/MARIA</speaker> Me? I loved him<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>BURR</speaker> And me? I’m the damn fool that shot him<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> There’s a million things I haven’t done<lb/> But just you
        wait!<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>BURR</speaker> What’s your name, man?<lb/></sp>

    <sp><speaker>COMPANY</speaker> Alexander Hamilton!<lb/></sp>
</root>
